- Mr. Szpilman? - Hello.
I came specially to meet you. I love your playing.
- Who are you? - My name's Dorota, Jurek's sister.
- You're bleeding! - It's nothing.
You can write him a fan letter later. This isn't the best time. Come on.
Jurek, where have you been hiding her?
- I don't know what to take. - You always take too much.
How many suitcases are you taking?
Take it, don't take it, take what you like.
Can't you see I'm worried sick?
He'll come home, he'll be alright.
- I should have another case. - Mama, Wladek is home!
Thank God. Wladek! You're wounded?
- No, it was nothing. - I've been worried sick.
I told her not to worry. You had your papers on you.
If you'd been hit by a bomb, they'd know where to take you.
Henryk, don't say things like that. God forbid. God forbid.
- Papa, Wladek is home. - What did I tell you?
- What are you doing? - Where's my hat with the wide brim?
- They've bombed us. We're off the air. - Warsaw is not the only radio station.
Pack, darling. Get your things packed.
- Where are we going? - Out of Warsaw.
- Out of Warsaw where? - You haven't heard?
- Heard what? - Haven't you seen the paper?
- Where's the paper? - I used it for packing.
- She used it for packing. - The government has moved to Lublin.
All men must leave the city, go across the river, set up a new line of defense.
There isn't anybody left here, only the women. The men are all gone.
What do you think you'll do while they set up a new line of defense?
- Wonder around with your suitcases? - Pack, Wladek. There's no time.
- I'm not going anywhere. - Good. I'm not going anywhere either.
Don't be ridiculous, we've got to keep together.
Look. If I'm going to die, I prefer to die in my own home, staying put.
- God forbid. - Shut up, I've got something. Listen.
...from the BBC in London. The British government...
has declared war on nazi Germany.
- That's wonderful! Wonderful! - It is expected that...
...within the next few hours, France will make a similar declaration.
Poland is no longer alone.
Wonderful, wonderful!
- Mama, that was a great dinner. - It certainly was.
When there's something to celebrate, you've got to make an effort.
Here's to Great Britain and France!
Didn't I tell you? Didn't I tell you? All will be well.
- Is that all? - Yes. It's all we've got left.
"Further restrictions regarding liquid assets.
Jews will be allowed to keep a maximum of 2,000 zlotys at home. "
- What do we do with the rest? - Deposit it in a bank. Blocked account.
Banks! Who'd be stupid enough to deposit money in a German bank?
We could hide the money. Look here. We can hide it under the flowerpots.
I'll tell you what we'll do. We'll use try and tested methods.
You know what we did in the last war?
We made a hole in the table leg, and hid the money in there.
- Suppose they take the table away? - What do you mean?
Germans go into Jewish homes and take furniture, valuables, anything.
- Do they? - Why'd they want a table like this?
- What on earth are you doing? - Listen. Look.
This is the best place. No-one would think of looking under the flowerpot.
- No, listen. I've been thinking... - Really? That's a change.
- You know what? We use psychology. - We use what?
We leave the money and the watch on the table, covered. In full view.
- Are you stupid? - The Germans will never notice it.
That's the stupidest thing I've ever seen. Of course they'll notice. Look.
Idiot.
- And you call me stupid. - Very good. That's the last place...
- This would take hours. - We're not in a hurry.
- It won't take hours. - How will you get them out? Tell me.
- You reach them out individually. - No-one listens to me!
Quiet, please, quiet. Order, order, please.
- The lawyer, she likes order. - Listen, just listen. Look.
The watch we put under the flowerpot and the money we stuff in the violin.
- But I'll still be able to play? - You'll find out.
- Jurek? It's Wladek Szpilman. - Wladek, how are you?
We're fine, thank you. And you?
Fine, under the circumstances. I guess I know why you're calling.
- Yes, I know, but I... - No music, no radio for the Polish.
But sure you'll find work. A pianist like you.
Maybe, maybe not, but...
don't be offended, but I didn't call to discuss my future carrier.
I nagged Jurek for weeks and weeks, and at last he gave in and said...
"All right, come with me tomorrow", so I came and...
they bombed the station.
- Meeting you like that was wonderful. - Really?
Yes, it was unforgettable.
- I love your playing, Mr. Szpilman. - Call me Wladek, please.
- No-one plays Chopin like you. - I hope it's a compliment.
- Of course, I mean it. - I was... trying to be funny.
- Should we go and have a coffee? - I'd like that.
- And you, what do you do? - I finished with the conservatoire.
- You're a musician? - Yes. But only just.
- What instrument? - The cello.
I love to see women playing the cello.
JEWS FORBIDDEN
This is disgraceful. How dare they?
You know what people are like, they want to be better nazis than Hitler.
- I'm going in there to complain. - It's better not, believe me.
- It's humiliating. Someone like you! - Good-bye.
We'll find somewhere else.
- We can walk in the park. - No, we can't.
- My God. Are you joking? - I'm not joking, it's true.
We could sit in a bench, but "no Jews allowed on public benches".
This is absurd.
We can just stand here and talk. I think we're allowed to do that.
So, you play the cello. That's nice. And who's your favorite composer?
Chopin? Really? Well...
you'll have to learn to play his cello sonata, won't you?
What about you, Wladek?
Perhaps I could accompany. Me on the piano, you on the cello.
Mr. Szpilman, you're quite, quite wonderful.
Call me Wladek, please.
"Free emblems for Jews in the Warsaw district.
I hereby order that all Jews in the Warsaw district...
will wear visible emblems when out of doors.
This decree will come into force on the first of December, 1939...
and applies to all Jews over 12 years of age.
The emblem will be worn on the right sleeve...
and will represent the blue star of David on a white background.
The background must be sufficiently large...
for the star to measure eight centimeters from point to point.
The width of the arms of the star must be one centimeter.
The Jews that do not respect this decree will be severely punished.
Governor of the Warsaw district, Dr. Fischer. "
- I won't wear it. - I'm not going to be branded.
Let me see this.
Does it say that we have to provide these armbands ourselves?
- Where will we get them? - We're not going to wear them.
Why haven't you greeted us?
I'm sorry.
The sidewalk is forbidden for you.
Go to the gutter.
- Have you seen this? - What? What? I'm working. What?
What is this?
- It's where they're going to put us. - What do you mean "put us"?
"By order of the governor of the Warsaw district, Dr. Fischer...
concerning the establishment of the Jewish district in Warsaw.
There'll be created a Jewish district in which Jews will have to reside. "
Look here. "Jews living outside of the prescribed area...
will have to move to the Jewish district by 31 of October, 1940."
They won't get all of us. It's too small.
There's 400 thousand of us in Warsaw.
No, 360 thousand. So it will be easy.
What am I supposed to do? You tell me.
Mama?
Mama, what is it?
20 zlotys!
That's all we have left, 20 zlotys.
What can I buy with 20 zlotys?
I'm sick of cooking potatoes, potatoes, potatoes.
That's the price. That's what I'm offering.
My advice is to accept. You won't get more from anyone else.
- But it's a Bechstein! - 2 thousand. My advice is to take it.
What are you going to do when you're hungry? Eat the piano?
- Get out! - What's the matter with you?
- Stop it! - We'd rather give it away. Get out!
Haven't you eaten today? What are you suffering from?
You people are crazy.
I'm doing you a favor. Two thousand and I'm paying for the removal.
I'm not even charging for the removal!
You haven't eaten today. You're crazy.
Take it.
Hello.
Hello. Hi.
I didn't want to come.
I didn't want to see all this, but... I couldn't stop myself.
- How are you doing? - Fine.
Good.
No, not really. They arrested my cousin.
Jurek says they'll let him out.
- This is disgraceful. - It won't last long. Don't worry.
That's what I said myself.
It's too absurd.
I... I should go.
Well, I'll see you...
Good-bye.
Well...
- Where will we sleep? - I sleep in the kitchen with the girls.
You, Henryk and papa, in here.
Look.
Come and look.
Go away! Go away!
Papa! Papa!
- Sell anything? - Just one. Dostoievski, "The Idiot".
- 3 zlotys. - It's better than yesterday.
Three lousy zlotys. And there are people there making millions.
- I know. - You don't know, believe me.
They bribe the guards, the guards turn a blind eye.
They bring cartloads of food, tobacco, liquor, French cosmetics.
And the poor are dying all around and they don't give a damn.
Excuse me, have you seen my husband, Izaak Szerman?
A tall handsome man, with a little gray beard.
- I'm afraid not. - Excuse me. Good-bye.
Sleep well. But if you see him, write to me, yes?
Izaak Szerman.
Why do we have to have a gentile street running through our area?
Why can't they go around?
Don't worry. They're about to build a bridge. Haven't you heard?
A bridge! Those idiots.
The Germans claim to be intelligent.
But do you know what I think? I think they're totally stupid.
I have a family to feed. I spend half of my time here...
waiting for them to let us through.
Maybe they think I come here to listen to the music?
Come on, come on! Dance!
Good, they're here.
Itzak Heller has been waiting for you.
- What's this about? - Sit down, have tea.
I'll start lunch when the girls get here.
- So, what are you doing here? - He brought cakes.
His father is back in the jewellery business. He's doing well.
Amazing, jewellery.
- We're recruiting. - Who is recruiting?
Don't be clever with me. I'm coming as a friend.
They're bringing Jews in from all over the country.
Soon there will be half million people in the ghetto.
- We need more Jewish police. - More Jewish police!
You want me to beat up Jews and catch the Gestapo spirit. I see.
- Someone has got to do it. - But why me?
I thought you only recruited boys with rich fathers.
Look at my father, look at us...
I'm looking at you, that's why I'm here. You can have a better life.
- You want to survive selling books? - Yes, please.
I'm doing you people a favor.
What about you? You're a great pianist.
We've got a police jazz band. They'd welcome you with open arms.
- Join us. You've got no work. - Thank you, I've got work.
I'm sorry, he wants you to stop.
Who wants me to stop?
I always say, look on the bright side.
You're in a small ghetto with intellectuals, professional people.
You're better off than us. Here in the large ghetto it's a cesspool.
- You have to give me something. - You're an artist...
you keep peoples' spirits up. You do enough.
- I want to help, do something. - You're too well known.
And you know what? You musicians don't make good conspirators.
You're too... too musical.
- Who is that? - Symche.
There are notices going up. City is to be cleansed of the undesirables.
- There's always notices going up. - Hello, Symche.
Dyrek. Mrs. Ysken.
Jehuda, working hard?
This is the greatest pianist in Poland. Maybe the whole world.
Wladyslaw Szpilman, meet Majorek.
- How do you do? - I know your name.
- I've never heard you play. - Majorek used to be in the Army.
Brilliant man. The only thing I've got against him is he's not a socialist.
You better go now, Wladek. It's nearly curfew.
You know how many copies we print of our newspaper?
Five hundred.
You know how many people on average read one copy? Twenty.
That makes 10 thousand readers. This will start the uprising.
Majorek hides them in his underpants and leaves them in toilets.
- Toilets? - As many toilets as I can find.
Germans never use Jewish toilets.
They're too clean for them.
Please, mister, please.
Stop it! Stop it!
Stop it!
Come on, come on. Come on, boy.
Stand up! Stand up.
Please, tonight for once, I don't want anything bad talked about.
- Enjoy your meal. - Then I'll tell you something funny.
- You know who I mean by Dr. Raszeja? - The surgeon.
The Germans allowed him into the ghetto to perform an operation.
On a Jew? They let a Pole to come in to operate on a Jew?
He got a pass, that's all I know. Anyway, so...
he puts the patient to sleep and starts the operation.
He'd just made the first incision when the SS burst in...
shoot the patient, then Dr. Raszeja and everybody else who was there.
Isn't that a laugh?
The patient didn't feel a thing, he was anesthetized.
I said nothing bad.
What's the matter with you all? You lost your sense of humor?
It's not funny.
You know what's funny? You're funny, with that ridiculous tie.
What are you talking about? What's my tie have to do with anything?
- I need this tie for my work. - Your work?
- That's right, I work. - Playing the piano for the parasites.
- Parasites... - Boys. Boys!
- They don't give a damn. - And you blame me for their apathy?
I see it everyday. They don't even notice what's going around them.
- I blame the Americans. - For what? For my tie?
The American Jews, and there are lots of them.
What do they think they're doing? People here are dying.
Haven't got a bite to eat.
The Jewish bankers should persuade America to declare war on Germany.
The lights! The lights!
You, stand up! Come on!
Mama...
- I'm Mr. Szpilman's sister. - Go in. Not you.
- What? - Come. It's terrible.
- What? - They're hunting people in the streets.
They've taken Henryk.
Go home, alright? Go home, I'll take care of it.
Excuse me. Have you seen my husband? Izaak Szerman?
- I'm afraid not. - Tall, handsome, little gray beard.
If you see him, write to me. Don't forget. Izaak Szerman.
What happened here?
They've got my grandson. They pick them up and take them away.
What they do to them, I've stopped believing in God.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Itzak?
- Henryk is in there. - I haven't seen him.
Believe me. They picked him up.
- Can you help? - Now you need me. Now you need me!
Can you help us?
- It costs. - I have no money.
Then there's nothing I can do. You should have joined us.
- They told me you had influence. - Who told you?
People I know. They said you're an important man.
Itzak...
- How are you? - You, bandit.
Dead! Dead!
- Want a cigarette? - Cigarette?
Thank you.
Help! Help!
Let go! Help!
- Why did they pick you up? - So you go to Itzak Heller?
- Did I ask you to talk to him? - You're out, aren't you?
- Did you beg to that piece of shit? - I asked him to help you.
What did you pay him?
With what could I pay him? Every zloty I earn we spend on food.
- I can look after myself. - They were taking you away.
It's got nothing to do with you. It's me they wanted, not you.
Why do you have to interfere with other people's business?
- You're mad. That's your trouble. - That's also my business.
Hungry.
Employment certificate. What's that mean, no employment certificate?
You have to have an employment certificate...
to work for the Germans in the ghetto, otherwise...
- Otherwise what? - You'll be deported.
- So the rumors were true. - They're going to resettle us...
and send us to labor camps, in the East.
- They're closing the small ghetto. - Oh, God!
Wladek? Wladek?
I thought you were on tour playing in London, Paris, New York, Chicago.
- Not this week. - You look terrible.
Have you heard the rumors? They're going to resettle us in the East.
Rumors! You take it all too much to heart. What's the trouble?
I've been trying to get the certificate of employment for my father.
I managed to get one for me and my family, but I need one for my father.
- I've been to all the firms and shops... - Why didn't you come to me?
I didn't know you were in the certificate business.
I'm not, but Majorek is.
Can you help? I have no money.
Please, don't insult us. Can you do something for him?
Be at the Schultz workshop tomorrow, four o'clock.
See what a wonderful piece of luck you've had today?
That's the historical imperative in action! That's why I always say:
- "Look on the bright side!" - Yes, I know.
- How's your back? - Better.
Better?
Better not ask.
- Thank you. - My pleasure. Won't help you anyway.
Thank you, Mr. Schultz.
At least we got work in the ghetto.
At least we are still together.
Everybody out! To the courtyard!
We are workers. We have employment certification.
You.
You. You.
The others, put your clothes on and come back here.
Bring your things with you. 15 kilos only.
Where are you taking us?
I'm sorry, I did my best.
- I thought the certificates'd save us. - Stop it, Wladek.
Let's just hope that Henryk and Halina will be better off.
- Where will we be going? - You're going to work.
You'll be much better off than in the stinking ghetto. Move.
Why did I do it? Why did I do it?
Why did I do it?
Don't you have a bottle of water? He's dying.
My child is dying of thirst.
- I beg you. - I'm sorry.
- Don't you have water? I beg you. - Can you hear what I'm saying?
- I'm telling you, it's a disgrace. - I can hear you.
Letting them take us to our death like sheep to the slaughter.
- Not so loud. - Why don't we attack them?
There's half a million of us here. We can break out of the ghetto.
At least we can die honorably, not as a stain on the face of History.
Why are you so sure they're sending us to our death?
You know why I'm not sure? Because they didn't tell me.
- They're going to wipe us all out. - What do you want me to do? Fight?
To fight, we need organization, plans, guns.
He's right. Do you think I'm going to fight with my violin bowl?
The Germans would never squander a huge labor force like this.
They're sending us to a labor camp, it's obvious.
Sure.
Look at you. You're going to carry logs on your back?
Henryk! Halina, Henryk!
I missed you. I wanted to be with you!
I wanted to be with you!
Stupid. Stupid.
Why did I do it? Why did I do it?
She's getting on my nerves.
- What did she do, for God's sake? - She smothered her baby.
They prepared a hiding place and of course they went there.
The baby cried just as the police came.
She smothered the cries with her hands, the baby died.
A policeman heard the death rattle and found where they were hiding.
What are you reading?
"If you prick us, de we not bleed? If you tickle us, do we not laugh?
If you poison us, do we not die?
And, if you wrong us, shall we not revenge?"
- Very appropriate. - Yes. That's why I brought it.
Idiot. What does he think he's gonna do with the money?
Boy, come here.
Come here.
- How much for a caramel? - 20 zlotys.
For one caramel? What do you think you're gonna do with the money?
20 zlotys.
We've got 20 between us.
I've got 10, I think.
5, 10, 20.
- Halina? - What?
- It's a funny time to say this, but... - What?
I wish I knew you better.
Thank you.
Szpilman?
Papa? Papa?
Mama? Halina?
Halina? Mama?
What do you think you're doing? I've saved your life. Just go! Go!
Don't run!
Anna!
Off they go to the melting pot.
What are you doing? She's pregnant.
Wladek?
Why are you here, Wladek?
It's like this, I...
We...
All of them, all of them.
All of them.
Perhaps they're lucky. The quicker, the better.
It's not finished yet. We'll stay here for a couple of days...
until things die down.
I've bribed the policeman, he'll come when it's over.
My God, I haven't been outside in, it must be two years.
Don't get overexcited.
It's gold. Very good price.
Someone you know?
A beauty. Who is she?
She's a singer. I knew her well. Her husband is an actor.
They're good people. I'd like to talk to her.
Don't forget, Wladek. They hang them for helping Jews.
Turn right!
How long have you been here?
Since last night.
I was pleased to see you.
They're going to start the final resettlement now.
We know what it means.
We sent someone out. Zygmund, a good man.
His orders were to follow the trains out of Warsaw.
He got to Sokolow.
A man told him the tracks divided, one branch's leading to Treblinka.
He said everyday freight trains carrying people from Warsaw...
branch off to Treblinka and return empty.
No transports of food are ever seen on that line.
The civilians are forbidden to approach the Treblinka station.
They're exterminating us.
It won't take them long.
We are 60 thousand left, out of half a million.
Mostly young people.
And this time we're gonna fight.
We're in good shape.
If you need help, I...
You! Come here!
Shit!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I don't know what I was thinking.
I hope you play the piano better than you carry bricks.
He won't last long if he goes on like this.
I'll see if I can get him something better.
Trouble.
Round up! Only the Jews.
The Polish keep working. Only the Jews.
I have good news for you.
There are rumors going around that we like to...
to resettle you.
I promise you that now and in the future...
nothing else is planned.
For this reason, we put information posters on the wall.
To show you our goodwill...
you should vote one of you to be allowed...
and bring 3 kilos of potatoes...
and one loaf of bread for each of your workers.
So, why should we do something like this if we'd resettle you?
You can make good business out of the things you don't eat.
Isn't that something that you Jews are good in? Making money?
Dismiss them.
That one, with the string. The others, tied by wire.
Now!
Majorek.
I have a favor to ask.
I want to get out of here.
It's easy to get out. It's how you'll survive on the other side that's hard.
I know.
Last summer, I worked for a day in the Zelazna Brama Square.
I saw someone I knew, she's an old friend.
A singer, her husband is an actor.
I've filled their names down and their address, if they're still there.
Janina Godlewska and Andrzej Bogucki. They're good people.
Would you try to make contact?
You go to town everyday. Ask them if they'd help me get out of here.
Have you got any plaster?
What are you up to?
What have you got there?
We are allowed to take food to the ghetto.
Three kilos of potato and bread.
Open it.
- It's only potatoes and bread. - You're lying. That's not true.
Potatoes!
You Jews are all alike.
We reach you with a finger...
and you take the whole hand.
If you lie to me again, I'll kill you. Personally.
I've tried your friends.
- They don't live there anymore. - Did you make contact?
- Be ready to leave. - When?
- Soon. - Halt!
Shit! Shit!
I'll teach you some discipline, you dirty Jews.
Do you know why you're being hit?
- No. - Do you know why you're being hit?
- Why? - To celebrate New Year.
On the march!
Sing something nice!
Loud and clear!
Reunite tonight And follow the white eagle
Stand up and fight Our mortal enemies
Rise on the day Let's give them fire and brimstone
I'm sorry.
We haven't much time. Come on.
We must hurry.
Here. See if this fit.
We have to keep moving you. Germans are hunting down indiscriminately.
Jews, non-Jews, anybody, everybody.
You better shave. Use my razor on the shelf.
You'll be looked after by Gebczynski.
He's on the other side of town.
You stay there tonight, then we'll find you somewhere else.
- I'll bring you food. - Alright, let's go.
I'll show you where you're going to sleep.
You have to stay here until tomorrow afternoon.
We have a flat for you near the ghetto wall. But it's safe.
It's not going to be very comfortable.
I'll be fine.
Thank you.
Here. Here. Give it to me.
Go as near to the front as possible, to the German section.
I'm going to draw the curtains now.
But you leave them open during the day. Don't forget.
Must feel better on this side of the wall, eh?
Yes.
But sometimes I'm still not sure which side of the wall I'm on.
Some bread, potatoes, onions.
I'll come again. Janina will visit you twice a week.
To bring more food, see how you are.
Thank you.
What do you mean you forgot?
What do you think I mean? I forgot, that's what I mean.
- You know, you treat me like dirt. - Because you are a dirt.
- Pig! Pig! - Bitch!
- Dirty pig! - You are a dirty pig!
Takes one to know one. Pig.
- You play like an angel. - Then why don't you listen?
- I'm listening. - Liar.
You fell asleep. Pig.
Shoot!
Thank you.
- I wanted to come earlier, but... - No, thank you.
No-one thought they'd hold out so long.
I never should've come out. I should have stayed and fought with them.
Wladek, stop that. It's over now.
Just be proud of them.
- My God, did they put up a fight! - Yes.
- So did the Germans. - They are in shock!
They didn't expect it. Nobody expected it. Jews fighting back.
- Who would have thought? - What good did it do?
What good?
Wladek, I'm surprised with you.
They died with dignity. And you know something else?
Now the Poles will rise. We are ready.
We'll fight too. You'll see.
Get your things together. You have to leave.
What? What's happened?
- I'm on the run. - What's happened?
The Gestapo found our weapons. They've arrested Janina and Andrzej.
They're bound to find out about this place too. You must get away at once.
Where do you want me to go?
Look at me, I'm not leaving.
- Can I take my chances here? - That's your decision.
But when they storm the flat, throw yourself out the window...
don't let them get you alive.
I have poison on me. They won't get me alive either.
Open up!
Open the door or we'll call the police!
Are you from this flat? You're not registered.
It belongs to a friend of mine. I just came to visit, but I missed him.
Have you got your identity card?
- Let me see your identity card. - Yes, of course.
- I want to see your identity card! - What's happening?
He's a Jew! A Jew!
Don't let him out! Stop him!
- Yes? - Mr. Gebczynski sent me.
- Wladyslaw Szpilman. - Dorota.
Come in.
I'm sorry.
Michal Dzikiewicz, he's my husband.
Come in.
Sit.
I need help.
He'll be back before curfew.
I've been in hiding.
- I need somewhere to stay. - He'll be here soon.
- How long have you been married? - Just over a year.
And how is Jurek?
Dead.
- When is your baby due? - Christmas.
This is not a good time to have children, but then...
This is my husband. Wladyslaw Szpilman.
- Marek Gebczynski sent him. - Yes, I remember.
He said to contact you only in case of emergency.
Don't worry now.
We can't move you tonight. You'll sleep on the sofa.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry, could I have a piece of bread?
Yes, of course. We will eat.
Sit. Please, sit.
Thank you.
You're on a very German area.
On the opposite is a hospital taking wounded from the Russian front.
And next door is the Schutzpolizei.
Safest place to be.
Right at the heart of the lion's den.
I'll be locking you in.
No-one knows you're here, so keep as quiet as possible.
All well?
Thank you.
This is Antek Szalas. He'll be looking after you.
- How do you do? - How do you do?
Thank you.
I've given him a second key. He'll bring food, see that you're alright.
He's with the underground, he's a good man.
- You don't remember me? - I don't think so.
Warsaw Radio. I was a technician.
I saw you almost everyday.
- I'm sorry, I don't remember. - It doesn't matter.
You've nothing to worry about. I'll visit often.
You'll be pleased to hear that the Allies are bombing Germany...
night after night, after night.
Cologne, Hamburg, Berlin.
And the Russians are giving them hell. It's the beginning of the end.
Let's hope so.
Still alive then?
Here. Sausage, bread.
You still got that vodka?
- How long is this meant to last? - Not long now.
I think I've got jaundice.
Don't worry about that. It just makes you look funny.
My grandfather was jilted by his girlfriend when he got jaundice.
Drink up.
Why didn't you come sooner? It's been over two weeks...
Problems.
Money.
I've got to raise money to buy the food.
I need things to sell, it's not easy.
Here. Sell this.
Food is more important than time.
Oh, yes. I meant to tell you! The Allies have landed in France.
Russians will be here soon.
They'll beat the shit out of the Germans...
any day now.
Wladek?
I knew it. I knew this would happen.
- I'll get a doctor. - You can't. It's too dangerous.
- Dr. Luczak. We can trust him. - Ridiculous. He's a pediatrician.
- He's still a doctor. - No.
You stay. I'll go.
We came to say goodbye.
We're going to stay with my mother in Otwocks.
The baby is already there. It's safer.
There's talk that the uprising will begin any day now.
That man Szalas should be shot.
He's been collecting money on your behalf all over Warsaw.
Apparently people gave generously, so he collected a tidy sum.
My God.
The liver the size of a football. Inflammation of the gall bladder...
but he'll leave.
I'll try to get him some laevulose, but it's not easy.
- Can you visit him again? - Who knows.
- Doctor, thank you. - Don't speak, rest.
Thank you so much for coming.
We've brought you some food.
I'll prepare something now for you, then we must go.
Get out, get out in the streets!
Get out now! The Germans have surrounded the building!
Somebody... Somebody help me!
What are you doing here?
Who are you?
- Do you understand? - Yes.
What are you doing?
I was...
trying to open this can.
Do you live here?
Do you work here?
No.
What do you do for a living?
I am...
I was a pianist.
Pianist?
Come.
Play something.
Are you hiding here?
Jew?
Where are you hiding yourself?
In the attic.
Show it to me.
Have you got anything to eat?
Attention!
- At ease. - At ease.
Jew?
Please.
What does it mean, all that shooting?
The Russians, on the other side of the river.
You just have to hold on a couple of weeks, not more.
- What's going on? - We're leaving.
- Are the Russians here? - Not yet.
I don't know how to thank you.
Thank God, not me.
He wants us to survive. At least, we have to believe in that.
- And you? - I have another one. Warmer.
What are you going to do when this is over?
I'll play piano again at the Polish radio station.
Tell me your name.
Maybe I'll listen to you playing.
Szpilman.
Perfect name for a pianist.
German! German!
I'm Polish!
- Come out with your hands up! - Please! I beg of you!
Don't shoot, don't shoot. I beg you, I'm a Polish.
Come down!
Please, I'm Polish. Please.
He's Polish.
Yes, he's Polish.
Why the fucking coat?
I'm cold.
Look at them. German fuckers!
Murderers! Murderers!
- Dirty bastards! - Assassins!
- Bastards! - Look at you now!
You took my violin, you took my soul.
Are you a musician?
Do you know...
a pianist called Szpilman, from the Polish radio station?
- Of course I know him. - I helped him to hide himself.
Tell him I'm here.
Ask him to help me.
- What's your name? - Hosenfeld.
What?
It was here, I'm certain of it.
Well, it's not here now.
I shouted, abused them. I'm not proud of it, but that's what I did.
I stood where you are now.
There was a barbed wire and this German came up to me.
- You didn't catch his name? - No.
I'll ask at the factory. They may know something.
(subtitle from http://shooter.cn by SPlayer1224
(subtitle from http://shooter.cn by SPlayer